Hello, and welcome to our English listening practice.
مرحبا بكم في تدريبنا على الاستماع إلى اللغة الإنجليزية.
How are you today?
كيف حالك اليوم؟
Do you feel that your listening is getting better
هل تشعر أن استماعك يتحسن؟
little by little?
شيئا فشيئا؟
I really hope so.
آمل ذلك حقا.
Today, I want you to imagine yourself in real
اليوم، أريدك أن تتخيل نفسك في الواقع
life situations and practice speaking English.
مواقف الحياة وممارسة التحدث بالإنجليزية.
For example, imagine you are at a hospital
على سبيل المثال، تخيل أنك في مستشفى
and you need to ask for help
ويجب أن تطلب المساعدة
or explain how you feel.
أو تشرح شعورك.
What would you say?
ماذا تقول؟
How would you understand the questions
كيف ستفهم الأسئلة
the doctor or nurse asks you?
هل يسألك الطبيب أو الممرضة؟
After this lesson, don't forget to tell me
بعد هذا الدرس، لا تنس أن تخبرني
how you feel after practicing with us.
كيف تشعر بعد التدريب معنا.
In today's lesson, I will share a short
في درس اليوم، سأشارك قصة قصيرة
simple story with you.
قصة بسيطة معك.
While traveling, I had many experiences
أثناء السفر، مررت بتجارب كثيرة
but one of the most stressful was when I had to visit
لكن أحد أكثر الأوقات توترا كان عندما اضطررت للزيارة
a hospital and couldn't explain what I needed.
مستشفى ولم أستطع شرح ما أحتاجه.
I avoided talking to anyone, the nurse, the doctor,
تجنبت التحدث مع أي شخص، الممرضة، الطبيب،
even the receptionist, because I couldn't understand
حتى موظفة الاستقبال، لأنني لم أستطع الفهم
what they were saying.
ما كانوا يقولونه.
But don't worry, in this video, you will learn
لكن لا تقلق، في هذا الفيديو ستتعلم
how to explain your situation politely and clearly
كيف تشرح وضعك بأدب ووضوح
in English.
بالإنجليزية.
When you visit a hospital, you will avoid the
عندما تزور المستشفى، ستتجنب
mistakes I made.
أخطاء ارتكبتها.
I will speak slowly and clearly, so you can
سأتحدث ببطء ووضوح، حتى تتمكن من ذلك
follow easily.
اتبع بسهولة.
If you want, you can repeat after me.
إذا أردت، يمكنك التكرار بعدي.
This will help your listening and speaking.
هذا سيساعدك على الاستماع والتحدث.
Are you ready?
هل أنت مستعد؟
Let's begin.
لنبدأ.